# **ERIK C. GUHLIN**

(281) 507- 3344 ~ ecguhlin@gmail.com

## INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY LEADER

## ENTERPRISE SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION ~ SYSTEMS ENGINEER ~ TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST

An **IT Professional** with a progressive 25+ year history of driving global IT projects and operations, managing and administering multiple enterprise solutions, and overseeing hardware and software systems across dynamic environments. Develops and delivers technical solutions in line with business objectives, executes IT initiatives to maintain uninterrupted operations, procures software, builds professional relationships across the globe, and leads/inspires IT project teams to meet and exceed targets. **Successfully Served as the Team Lead for a Global Windows 7 Image Creation and Migration.** 

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

IT Project Management ~ Quality Assurance ~ Global Migrations ~ Data Analysis ~ Captures Cost Savings ~ Software Procurement Improves IT Security Levels ~ Image Creation ~ Technical Training ~ Systems Engineering ~ End-User and Desktop Support

### **CERTIFICATIONS/PROFESSIONAL LICENSES**

Certified Software Asset Manager (CSAM) – IAITAM
Certified Hardware Asset Management Professional (CHAMP) – IAITAM

## **CAREER HISTORY**

AMERICAN BUREAU OF SHIPPING (ABS): Houston, TX

SYSTEMS ENGINEER II/Tier 3 Desktop Support (2007 – Present)

5/2005 - Present

Led IT global processes and projects throughout their lifecycles while administering enterprise systems and designing/deploying process improvements to maximize efficiency and quality across the organization.

#### HIGHLIGHTED INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY PROJECT ACCOLADES AND RESULTS

- Team Lead: Global Windows 7 Image Creation. Created a Windows 7 image to function globally through the use of Windows Automated Installation Kit (WAIK).
- ➤ Team Lead: Global Windows 7 Migration from Windows XP. Coordinated with executives across the globe, including China, Japan, South Korea, Singapore, London, Greece, Sweden, Denmark, Norway, Poland and Brazil, to complete the migration across 200 countries with minimal interruptions to business operations.
- > Tier 3 Desktop Support. Coordinated support for the desktop team and resolved any issues that could not be solved by the desktop team. Support includes Windows 7 Enterprise, Windows 10 Enterprise and Office 365
- ➤ Cherwell Asset Management Implementation (CAM). Configured a Windows 2008 server for use with CAM. Led the installation, configuration, and deployment to global computers via SCCM. The project allowed the organization to identify and manage assets, reclaim unused licenses, redeploy available machines, and capture cost savings.
- > OpenLM Implementation: Saved the Firm \$500K Annually and Reduced the Number of Licenses by Up to 30%. This tool enabled software license usage data analyzation and allowed the initiation and enforcement of usage data policy in floating licenses.
- > Cyberark Endpoint Privilege Manager (Formerly Viewfinity) Implementation. Improved security posture and halted malware proliferation by utilizing the Least Rights Management platform, removing administrative rights from user machines, and assigning administrative rights, at the application level, only on an as-needed basis.
- Reduced Customer Internal Software Delivery Times from 3 Days to the Same Business Day while reducing email numbers by automating the internal software requests and approval processes.

### **HIGHLIGHTED RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Provided Consultative Leadership to Manage and Empower Project Teams of seven to exceed performance targets.
- Procured, Assessed, Implemented, Supported, and Administered Enterprise Solutions and Corporate IT Assets, including McAfee ePO (VSE, Drive Encryption, and DLP), Cyberark EPM (Least Rights Management Formerly Viewfinity), Cherwell Asset Management, Express Metrix, OpenLM (License Management and Reclamation), CylanceProtect (Endpoint Security), and license servers utilizing FlexLM, RLM, WLM, HASP, and Sentinel.
- Recognized for Superior Performance with a Series of Promotions, including Desktop Support III, Quality Assurance Analyst, Systems Engineer, and Systems Engineer II. Consistently rated in the top 20% in a department of 50+ people.

# ERIK C. GUHLIN ~ (281) 507-3344 ~ ecguhlin@gmail.com

> Steered the Worldwide Distribution of Engineering Software and supported software and licensing issues.

## American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) Continued

#### **SENIOR DESKTOP ADMINISTRATOR** (2005 – 2007)

Delivered expert second/executive level support to maintain maximum uptime across one of the world's leading ship classification societies. Managed and supported infrastructures, servers, and numerous operating systems: Win95, 98, ME, 2000, XP and Server 2003, MS Office 2000/2003, Oracle, and multiple proprietary applications.

- > Tapped as a Technical Liaison for the Desktop Support Team and Delivered Third-Level Support, as needed, while concurrently serving as a desktop support technician.
- Designed, Deployed, and Led a Technical Support Project charged with conducting preventative maintenance on technical resources and supporting ABS field surveyors.
- > Performed Root Cause Analysis to Resolve a Variety of Technical Issues and minimize/eliminate service interruptions.
- Provided End-User Training on IT Protocols/Best Practices and Communicated Technical Jargon to Non-Technical Users.
  Provided examples and step-by-step instructions to troubleshoot/resolve issues and built positive rapport with users across diverse cultural backgrounds and technical expertise.

### SIMMONS AND COMPANY INTERNATIONAL: Houston, TX

1/2003 - 5/2005

#### **SYSTEMS ENGINEER**

Provided desktop support, technical/IT training, and software and hardware administration to maintain a productive working environment.

- Sourced, Assessed, and Procured Software Solutions able to meet the critical technical needs of the organization within budgets. Tested each one for ease of use, bugs, and network integration abilities, formulated reports, and made recommendations to management on each program.
- Cultivated and Maintained Technical Expertise to Resolve a Variety of Network Issues, including TCP/IP and Citrix (client side) in evolving technical environments.
- > **Set Up Laptops in Multiple Offsite Connections** to allow traveling personnel to seamlessly continue working across diverse geographic locations.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION & COMPUTER SCIENCE COURSES**

SAM HOUSTON STATE UNIVERSITY

## **COMPUTER SCIENCE OPERATING SYSTEMS**

NORTH HARRIS COMMUNITY COLLEGE

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

OPERATING SYSTEMS
DOS 6.22, Win 3.1, 95, 98, ME NT, 2000, XP, 7, 8, 10 Server 2000-12, Novell 4.x-5.x
OFFICE SUITES
Microsoft Office 95 – 2016, Access, Excel, PowerPoint, Word, and Adobe Applications

EMAIL: Lotus Notes and Microsoft Outlook (Exchange)

TICKETING SYSTEMS: Heat, Reachout, Track-IT

DATABASE APPLICATIONS: Oracle, Access & SQL (Support and Troubleshooting)
COMMUNICATIONS: Cisco VPN, Remote Desktop, Hyper-Terminal, FTP, Telnet

NETWORK: Client for Microsoft Networks, Client Service for Netware, TCP/IP, NetBIOS, WINS, IPX/SPX HARDWARE: System Boards, ROM, RAM, PCI, ISA, USB, SCSI, IDE, Firewire, Processors, Fans, NICs,

Video Adapters, Sound Adapters, Modems, Parallel, Serial, Hard Disks, CD/DVD ROMs, Floppy

Disks and all Cabling and Connections

### UNITED STATES ARMY MILITARY HISTORY